Guide to the Earl S. Markham papers, 1908-1938, bulk 1912-1919
Markham, Earl S. papers, 1908-1938, bulk 1912-1919
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Earl S. Markham papers, 1908-1938, bulk 1912-1919
37-05-3359
Markham, Earl S.
0.6 cubic ft.
photographs, notebooks, texts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs and ephemera relating to Earl Markham's education at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine as well as his service in the United States Army Veterinary Corps during World War I.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Earl Markahm was Born on February 20, 1887, in Constableville, New York. He attended the Utica School of Commerce in Utica from 1907-1908, then went on to the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, where he received his DVM in 1912. His brother, Miles Markham, was also a graduate of the college, DVM 1918.
From 1917-1919 he served in the U.S. Army Veterinary Corps at the Remount Service in Kansas City, Missouri, and at Remount Depot #333, Camp Joseph E. Johnston, in Jacksonville, Florida.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs and ephemera relating to Earl Markham's education at the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine as well as his service in the United States Army Veterinary Corps during World War I.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Markham, Earl S.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.; United States Army. Veterinary Corps.
Subjects:
Veterinarians.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Veterinary service.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Given by Sandra Markham in December 2003.
CONTAINER LIST
- Photograph - Earl Markham's Cornell class photo, 1912 (Box 1)
- Photograph - Cornell Class of 1912 group photo (Box 1)
- Photograph - New York State Veterinary College Class of 1912 composite (Box 1)
- Photographs - Cornell Classmates - Identified, ca. 1912 (Box 1)
- Photographs - Cornell Classmates - Unidentified, ca. 1912 (Box 1)
- Photograph - Earl Markham in uniform, ca. 1916-1919 (Box 1)
- Photographs - Miscellaneous military snapshots, ca. 1916-1919 (Box 1)
- Photographs - negs of military photos, ca. 1916-1919 (Box 1)
- Photographs - 7 tightly rolled military photos, ca. 1916-1919 (Box 1)
- Fraternity newsletter - The Torch of Alpha Psi, ca. 1938 (Box 1)
- Photo Album - mostly family, some military, ca. 1900-1940 (Box 2)
- Photo Album - mostly military, some family, ca. 1916-1919 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous military and veterinary guides and texts, ca. 1908-1919 (Box 2)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Earl Markham's World War I uniform was removed from this collection and given to the Cornell Costume Collection.